Mss.Rec.170 Mss.Rec.170
American Philosophical Society
Panamint language recordings
1983
Mss.Rec.170
American Philosophical Society
9.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings, recorded at Ridgecrest, California in 1983. Elicited vocabulary and grammar, with English glosses and frequent commentary on Panamint history and customs. Includes an interview with the consultant by a newspaper reporter on his life and local history.
9 sound cassettes (7 hr., 50 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Certini, Rose
Hanson, Dugan
Shaul, David
Location of Originals
Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Audiocassette copies or original tapes prepared the Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley
Conditions Governing Access
Restricted access. Requires permission of Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley.
Related Archival Materials
The researcher's transcripts from these recording sessions and notes on tape duplication from Berkeley Language Center are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by David Shaul in 1987 (Acc. 1987-854r) in the form of audiocassette copies of original tapes prepared by the Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Panamint Indians; Panamint language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Elicitation of numbers, 1983-02-15; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:45; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Scope and Contents note
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 1:1.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Elicitation of terms for kin and people, 1983-02-15; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:54; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
  - Elicitation of terms for parts of the body, 1983-02-15; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:16; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Human body--Terminology; Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Elicitation of terms for parts of the body, 1983-02-15; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:01; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 1:2.
  - Elicitation of terms for colors, 1983-02-15; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:26; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Colors, Words for; Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Elicitation of terms for natural phenomena and directions, 1983-02-15; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:06; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 2:1-2:2.
    Hopi Indians; Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Elicitation of terms for animals and plants, 1983-02-15; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:27; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 2:2.
  - Elicitation of terms for artifacts and foods, 1983-02-17; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:17; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 2:3.
  - Elicitation of adjectives and verbs, 1983-02-17; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:35; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
  - Elicitation of verbs, 1983-02-17; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:58; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 3:1.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases, 1983-02-17; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:51; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous words, 1983-02-17; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:14; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
  - Interview with the Daily Independent about the consultant's life and memories [1 of 2], 1983-02-16; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:38; Certini, Rose; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 4:1.
    Indians of North America--California; Panamint Indians--Government relations; Panamint Indians--History; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Interview with the Daily Independent about the consultant's life and memories [2 of 2], 1983-02-16; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:26; Certini, Rose; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 4:2-4:3.
    Indians of North America--California; Panamint Indians; Panamint Indians--History; Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.); Tipis
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases, 1983-02-24; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:50; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 5:1.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases, 1983-02-24; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:50; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 5:2.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "antelope" to "beads", 1983-02-24; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:43; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 6:1.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "bear" to "cloudy", 1983-02-24; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:51; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 6:2.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "coals" to "dragonfly", 1983-02-25; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:40; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 7:1.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "dreaming" to "great-grandmother", 1983-02-25; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:39; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 7:2.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "hail" to "knee", 1983-02-25; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:24; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 8:1.
    Birds--California; Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.)
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "lake" to "navel", 1983-02-26; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:42; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 8:2.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "necklace" to "porcupine", 1983-02-26; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:20; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 9:1.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "pregnant" to "sparrow", 1983-02-26; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:22; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 9:2.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "spread" to "two", 1983-02-26; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:39; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 10:1.
  - Discussion of seeds good for eating, 1983-02-26; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Panamint language; Ridgecrest (Calif.); Seeds as food
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases: "umbilical cord" to "zigzag", 1983-02-26; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:58; Hanson, Dugan; Shaul, David
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Formerly numbered 10:2.